TOP GUN OVER MOSCOW

For half a century we feared them. Now, for the first time, meet the rugged pilots of the Russian Air Force - and take a close-up look at the heart-stopping maneuvers that still fill Western flyers with awe.

Check out the "cobra": coiling up and back like a snake, a jet fighter evades the chasing enemy and becomes the pursuer. See vintage footage of the notorious taran, when wartime pilots would ram their foes in mid-air. Join aviation author Jeff Ethell as he tests out the powerful Su-27 - and gets goaded into pulling a hair-raising stunt. Then take a $15,000 ride aboard a bomber jet with a US thrill seeker (one measure of Russia's desperate economy), complete with stomach-turning g-forces. "I call it the zoom-boom-throw-up-in-your-helmet ride," a veteran pilot smirks.

Find out why, despite baffling differences in approach, Western aces see these fearless flyers as a formidable force - honing their dogfight tactics over the technology we so depend on. "We build our planes like fine watches," one American expert notes. "And they build theirs like tanks."

DISCOVER YOUR WORLD WITH NOVA

When it comes to the world around us, no one helps you understand it better than NOVA. Since 1973, NOVA has been sharing "adventures in science," exploring and explaining the fascinating mysteries that surround us to millions of viewers each week. NOVA tackles its subjects in an entertaining, enlightening and educational way, which accounts for the numerous Emmy Awards, critical acclaim from the entertainment and scientific communities, and devotion from the viewing public. America's longest-running and most-watched science program now comes to home video and invites you inside its exciting world. For young and old alike, NOVA is the perfect addition to every home video library.


Approximate Running Time: 60 Minutes ID
Color/Not Rated/VHS
Produced and Directed by Lance K. Shula and Lynne Squill, Written by Lynne Squills. Executive Producer Paula S. Apsell. A NOVA Production by Auburn Productions for WGBH/Boston. 1996 WGBH Educational Foundation. All rights reserved.
Photo © Uniphoto/Check Six

To order this and other NOVA Videos contact WGBH Video, PO Box 2284, South Burlington, VT 05407-2284. Call 800-255-9424, Fax 802-864-9846. Internet address: http://www.wgbh.org.

NOVA' is a registered trademark of WGBH Educational Foundation. NOVA is made possible by grants from Merck, Prudential, the Corporation for Public 
Broadcasting and public television viewers.

WGBH BOSTON VIDEO
